we need to determine
what the code we've been given will
output
and to do so we need to look closely at
the method definition
for the tricky number method
within this method we have an if
statement
this first branch of the if statement
will be executed
if the condition that we provide is
truthy or evaluates as true
we've provided the boolean true so the
first branch of this if statement will
be executed
every time this method is invoked and
therefore
the else branch of our if statement will
never be executed
within the if clause on line three you
can see we have a variable assignment
we are assigning the integer one to a
variable
number now we don't use this variable
number
anywhere else in the code however we
need to understand the return value of
variable assignment
the return value of variable assignment
is the value itself
in this case the integer one
as a result our method returns to
integer 1
because that is the evaluated result of
the last line executed in the tricky
number method
remember that our else clause will not
be evaluated
so on line nine when we output the
return value of tricky number
we expect that we will be outputting one
and let's run our code and see that
as expected we output one
if the condition provided to our if
statement
were falsy we can place the boolean
false here
on line two then the if clause would not
be executed
however the else clause would be that
means that ruby would
evaluate line five the integer 2
and 2 would become the return value of
our tricky number method
so let's run our code again now with
ruby evaluating the
else clause
you can see that the return value of our
method is now
two
so it's important to understand that the
return value of variable assignment
as we see on line three is the value
that was assigned to the variable